Forget it. It's too risky.
I'm through doing that shit.
You always say that.
The same thing every time.
"I'm through, never again,
too dangerous."
I know that's what I always say.
I'm always right too.
You forget about it in a day or two.
The days of me forgetting are over.
The days of me remembering
have just begun.
You know, when you go on like this,
what you sound like?
I sound like a sensible fuckin' man.
You sound like a duck.
Quack, quack, quack. Take heart, 'cause
you're never gonna have to hear it again.
Since I'm never gonna do it again, you're
never gonna have to hear me quack.
After tonight? Correct. I
got all tonight to quack.
Can I get anyone more coffee?
Oh, yes!
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I mean, the way it is now,
you're takin' the same risk
as when you rob a bank.
Takin' more of a risk.
Banks are easier.
Federal banks ain't supposed to stop
you in any way during a robbery.
They're insured. Why should they give a fuck?
I don't even need a gun in a federal bank.
Heard about this one bloke, he walks
into a bank with a portable phone.
He gives the phone to a teller.
The bloke on the other end says,
"We got this guy's little girl. If you don't
give him all your money, we're gonna kill her."
- Did it work?
- Fuckin' right it worked. That's what I'm talkin' about.
Knucklehead walks into a bank with a telephone,
not a pistol, not a shotgun, a fuckin' phone.
Cleans the place out. They don't lift a fuckin' finger.
Did they hurt the little girl?
There probably never was a little girl.
The point of the story isn't a little girl.
The point of the story is they
robbed a bank with a telephone.
- You want to rob banks?
- I'm not saying I wanna rob banks.
I'm illustrating if we did, it'd be
easier than what we've been doing.
- No more liquor stores?
- What've we been talkin' about? Yeah, no more liquor stores.
Besides, it ain't the giggle it used to be.
There's too many foreigners own liquor stores.
Vietnamese, Koreans,
don't even speak fuckin' English.
You tell 'em empty out the register, they
don't know what you're talkin' about.
They make it too personal.
We keep on, one of these gook fuckers gonna
make us kill him. I'm not gonna kill anybody.
I don't want to either. But they'll probably
put us in a situation where it's us or them.
And if it's not the gooks,
it's these old fuckin' Jews who've owned
the store for 15 fucking generations.
You got Grandpa Irving sitting behind the
counter with a fucking Magnum in his hand.
Try walkin' into one of those places
with nothing but a phone.
See how far that gets you.
Forget it.
We're out of it.
Well, what then, day jobs?
Not in this life.
What then?
Garcon, coffee!
This place.
Garcon means boy.
This place?
A coffee shop?
What's wrong with that?
Nobody ever robs restaurants.
Why not?
Bars, liquor stores,
gas stations; you get your head
blown off stickin' up one of them.
Restaurants, on the other hand,
you catch with their pants down.
They're not expectin' to get robbed.
Not as expectin' anyway.
I bet you could cut down on the hero
factor in a place like this. Correct.
Same as banks,
these places are insured.
Manager.
He don't give a fuck.
They're just trying to get you out
before you start pluggin' the diners.
Waitresses. Fuckin' forget it. No way
they're takin' a bullet for the register.
Busboys. Some wetback gettin'
paid $1 .50 an hour...
really give a fuck you're
stealin' from the owner?
Customers sittin' there with food in their
mouths, they don't know what's goin' on.
One minute, they're havin' a Denver omelet, the
next, someone is stickin' a gun in their face.
See, I got the idea the last liquor
store we stuck up, remember?
- All the customers kept comin' in.
- Yeah.
You got the idea of takin' their wallets.
Now, that was a good idea.
- Thank you.
- Made more from the wallets than we did from the register.
Yes, we did. A lot of
people come to restaurants.
- A lot of wallets.
- Pretty smart, huh?
Pretty smart.
I'm ready. Let's do it.
Right now, right here.
Come on. All right. Same
as last time, remember?
You're crowd control.
I'll handle the employees.
I love you, pumpkin.
I love you, honey bunny.
Everybody be cool!
This is a robbery!
Any of you fucking pricks move,
and I'll execute every motherfuckin'
last one of you.
♪♪ ["MISIRLOU"]
[RADIO DIAL TUNING]
♪♪ ["JUNGLE BOOGIE"]
♪Jungle boogie ♪
♪ Get down with the boogie ♪
♪Jungle boogie ♪ ♪ Get it on ♪
♪Jungle boogie ♪
♪ Get down with the boogie ♪
♪Jungle boogie ♪ ♪ Get it on ♪
♪Jungle boogie ♪
♪ Get up with the boogie ♪
♪ Get up with the get down ♪
♪Jungle boogie ♪
♪ Get down and boogie ♪
♪ Shake it around ♪♪
Okay, so tell me again about the hash bars.
Okay, what you want to know?
Hash is legal there, right? Yeah,
it's legal, but it ain't 100% legal.
You just can't walk into a restaurant,
roll a joint and start puffin' away.
I mean, they want you to smoke in your
home or certain designated places.
Those are hash bars? Yeah.
It breaks down like this.
It's legal to buy it.
It's legal to own it.
And if you're the proprietor
of a hash bar, it's legal to sell it.
It's illegal to carry it, but-but that
doesn't matter, 'cause get a load of this.
If you get stopped by a cop in Amsterdam,
it's illegal for them to search you.
I mean, that's a right the cops in
Amsterdam don't have. Oh, man! I'm goin'.
That's all there is to it.
I'm fuckin' goin'.
I know, baby.
You'd dig it the most.
But you know what the funniest
thing about Europe is? What?
It's the little differences. I mean, they got
the same shit over there that they got here,
- but it's just there, it's a little different.
- Example.
You can walk into a movie theater
in Amsterdam and buy a beer.
And I don't mean just like no paper cup.
I'm talkin' about a glass of beer.
And in Paris, you can buy a beer in McDonald's.
You know what they call...
a Quarter Pounder
with Cheese in Paris?
They don't call it
a Quarter Pounder with Cheese?
They got the metric system. They wouldn't
know what the fuck a quarter-pounder is.
- What do they call it?
- They call it a Royale with Cheese.
Royale with Cheese.
That's right.
What do they call a Big Mac?
Big Mac's a Big Mac,
but they call it Le Big Mac.
[IMITATING FRENCH ACCENT]
Le Big Mac. [LAUGHS]
What do they call a Whopper? I don't know.
I didn't go into Burger King.
You know what they put on french fries
in Holland instead of ketchup? What?
Mayonnaise. [
Chuckles] Goddamn!
I seen 'em do it, man. They fuckin'
drown 'em in that shit. Yuck.